Guide to the Datus C. Proper Papers 1864-2003
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
- Subject Vertical Files, 7
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Miscellaneous Species - Sinking (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Miscellaneous Species - Wet (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Montana Hatches (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Sedges (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Stoneflies (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Flies-Natural and Artificial and Other Trout Foods: Terrestrials - Ants, Beetles, etc. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Fly Fishing Methods: Dry Flies (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Fly Fishing Methods: Fly Casting (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Fly Fishing Methods: Nymph Methods (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Fly Fishing Methods: Vince Marinaro (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Fly Fishing Methods: Wet Flies (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Fly Tackle: Fly Rods (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Fly Tackle: Fly Rods - Care and Construction (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Fly Tackle: Fly Rods - Technical (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Fly Tackle: Pezon et Michel (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Fly Tackle: William Mills and Son, Inc. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Fly Tackle: Hooks - Design, Strength, etc. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Fly Tackle: Leaders (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Fly Tackle: Lines (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Fly Tackle: Reels (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Fly Tying: Dubbing (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Fly Tying: Fly Behavior and Designs (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Fly Tying: Notes (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Fly Tying: Hackles (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Fly Tying: Origin of Old Fly Designs (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Fly Tying: Salmon Fly Tying (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Fly Tying: Streamers, Fly Rod Lures (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Fly Tying: Trout Fly Tying - Technical (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Guns (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Guns and Shooting: American (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Guns and Shooting: English (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Guns and Shooting: Purchases (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Guns and Shooting: Shotguns (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Hunting: Big Game - American (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Hunting: Big Game - Foreign (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Hunting: Bird Habitat and Cover - Articles (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Hunting: Bird Habitat and Cover - Letters and Notes (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Hunting: Grouse (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Hunting: History, Reasons, etc. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hunting: Non-Game Species (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hunting: Partridges (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Hunting: Pheasants (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hunting: Quail (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hunting: Snipe, Woodcock, Rails, Doves (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Hunting: Upland Game Management (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hunting: Virginia Hunting Maps (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hunting: Waterfowl and Other Birds (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Angling Humor (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Bait and Lures (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Bass (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Ethics (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Fishing (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: History (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Philosophy (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Rapidan TU Project (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Other Fish and Fishing: Yellowstone Area Fishing (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Boating, Float Tubes (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Books (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Books - Collection (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Books - Laid in Materials (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Books - Laid in Material (2) (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Camping and Gear (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Flyfisher's Classic Library (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Honey Dun Press (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Knives, Axes, etc. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Nature Misc. - Weather (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Optics, Photography (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Outdoor Clothing and Boots (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Stream Access (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Waders, Vests, Floatants, Nets, etc. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Outdoor and Miscellaneous: Writing (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Places: Africa, Asia, Pacific (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Places: Canada (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Places: Europe (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Places: Midwest (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Places: Montana - Hunting and Fishing (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Places: Northwestern U.S. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Places: Portugal (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Places: South America and Caribbean (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Places: Southern U.S. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Places: Washington D.C. Area (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Fishery Management (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Lakes (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Stream Chemistry (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Stream Ecology (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Stream Plants (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Streams and Lakes (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Resource - Streams and Lakes: Trees and Plants (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Color (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Fish Vision (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Grayling, Whitefish, etc. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Rise Forms (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Trout Behavior, Selectivity, etc. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Trout Species (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Trout and Other Salmonids: Salmon, Steelhead, Sea Trout (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Memorial Service Materials, 2002-2003; 8
  Proper's memorial service materials include a small set of documents from his funeral and letters of condolence to his widow. They feature obituaries, testimonials, and a recording of his funeral service.
  - Obituaries and Funeral Programs (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters of condolence (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Funeral Service [VHS] (Box 16, Vhs 1)
- Photographs, 9
  Proper's photographs feature sets of 35mm slides and prints he selected for use in his publications. Although most were never featured in his published works, the images relate to topics addressed in Proper's books and articles including fly tying, trout stream fishing, and hunting dogs. Several sets of prints also document his travels in Portugal, which he detailed in his 1993 book, The Last Old Place: A Search Through Portugal. A very small set of photos include photos of Proper during his childhood and portraits of him as an adult.
  - Slides, topical (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Adriano (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - The Best of It (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Black (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Book-Home-#4 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - British Mayfly (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Dogwood Run (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Hellroaring Creek (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Huck (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Humility Creek (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Slides, topical (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Humility Creek (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Fishing for Shadows (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Jack Heddon, letter of August 3, 1988, 1988 August 3 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - A Perfect Stream (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - A Place of Our Own (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Portugal, Trout (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Vince Marinaro (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - What The Trout Said (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Unlabeled slides (1) (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Unlabeled Slides (2) (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Photographs 1-11 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Datus C. Proper (DCP), 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 1)
    - DCP, 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 2)
    - DCP, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 3)
    - DCP, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 4)
    - DCP, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 5)
    - DCP, 1935 November (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 6)
    - DCP (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 7)
    - DCP and friend, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 8)
    - DCP and siblings, 1942 December 2 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 9)
    - DCP, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 10)
    - DCP, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 12, Photographic-print 11)
  - Photographs 12-22 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - DCP, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 12)
    - DCP, circa 1990s (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 13)
    - DCP, circa 1990s (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 14)
    - DCP and colleagues, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 15)
    - DCP and colleagues, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 16)
    - Portugal photographs (Box 16, Folder 13, Photographic-print 17-22)
  - Photographs 23-31 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Home place photographs (Box 16, Folder 14, Photographic-print 23-29)
    - Vince Marinaro (Box 16, Folder 14, Photographic-print 30-31)
  - Numbered Negatives (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Unnumbered Negatives (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Published Images (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Maps, Tracings, Certificates and Awards (oversize) (Box 17)